RG 082, State Planning Board
Connecticut State Library
State Planning Board records
1933-1937
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. State Planning Board
.5 cubic feet
The State Planning Board coordinated and integrated information pertaining to growth and development of the State. They collected information, data and maps from across departmental lines and made the information available to all. There were several projects initiated by the Board relating to water quality, forests, highways, population demographics and zoning. An aerial map of the State was considered “the most essential single step for our state-wide data.”
RG082
Historical Note
In the summer of 1933, President Roosevelt created the National Planning Board, later to become the National Resources Board. That same year, Governor Wilbur L. Cross appointed a Connecticut State Planning Board. The Board coordinated and integrated information pertaining to growth and development of the State. They collected information, data and maps from across departmental lines and made the information available to all. There were several projects initiated by the Board relating to water quality, forests, highways, population demographics and zoning. An aerial map of the State was considered “the most essential single step for our state-wide data.” [Connecticut State Planning Board, Statement #9, April 4, 1934. CSL call number: ConnDoc P693 st] In 1935, the General Assembly passed legislation officially creating the State Planning Board, which superseded the so-called Governor’s Board created under executive authority.
Scope and Content
These records consist of reports and summary of work.
Related Material
RG 005:026, Wilbur L. Cross gubernatorial records, 1931-1939.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. State Planning Board
Subjects:
Connecticut. State Planning Board -- Records and correspondence; Regional planning -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Reports
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Reports, 1933-1937
  - Davis, I. G. "Agricultural Production in New England." In New England's Prospect, 1933. New York: American Geographical Society: 1933. (Box 1)
    This is reference material.
  - "Report - January 12th to July 12th 1934" by George H. Gray, Planning Consultant to the Connecticut state Planning Board from the National Resources Board., typescript, 3 copies (Box 1)
  - "Report to the Connecticut State Planning Board for the first six months work January 12 to July 12, 1934" by George H. Gray., typescript (Box 1)
  - "Report on Land Planning Agencies and Data" prepared by George H. Gray, Director & Planning Consultant, Connecticut State Planning Board, August 25, 1934, to L. C. Gray, Director, Land Section, National Resource Board., typescript (Box 1)
  - "A Condensed Report on Planning for Connecticut" by George H. Gray, Planning Consultant, Based on Experience to October 9, 1934) to Charles W. Eliot, 2nd, Executive Officer of the National Resource Board, In Compliance with Bulletin #B-5., typescript (Box 1)
  - Director's report, 1935 September 24; typescript (Box 1)
  - "Development of State Provision for Recreation" by Connecticut State Planning Board, 1936. (Box 1)
  - Report of the State Planning Board to Governor Wilbur L. Cross. (Hartford, Conn., December 14, 1934., 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Summary of Work of the Connecticut State Planning Board; Report to His Excellency Governor Wilbur L. Cross. (Hartford, Conn., January 1, 1937., 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Summary of Work of the Connecticut State Planning Board; Report to His Excellency Governor Wilbur L. Cross. January 1, 1937., typescript (Box 1)